

MOHAMAD FAJAR MAHARDIKA

Surabaya, Indonesia | P: 6281232522330 | mf.mahardika@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/massffajar/ | https://github.com/fajarmhr/

PROFILE

Fresh graduate from Telkom University majoring in Telecommunication Engineering. I am self-motivated, reliable, curious and fast learner person. Currently aim to gain more knowledge and experience in Cloud Computing and Mobile Core Network. I am able to work independent and/or in team, I also have developed good planning and organizational skills by participated in several positive activities.

FORMAL EDUCATION

TELKOM UNIVERSITY Sep 2017 – Feb 2023

Bachelor of Telecommunication Engineering, Cumulative GPA: 3.32/4.0

INFORMAL EDUCATION

BANGKIT ACADEMY Feb 2021 – Jul 2021

Studying about Google Cloud Computing

HUAWEI CLOUD TRAINING

Aug 2020 – Dec 2020

Preparation to take part in Huawei Cloud Certification and also preparation to take part in Huawei ICT Competitions

WORK EXPERIENCE

Basic and Applied Research

Mobile Core Analyst

Mar 2023

- Project with lecturers to follow up on my thesis about implementing an open-source 5G network, so it can be published in Sinta 2 journals.
- Analyze log from each 5G Core NF (AMF, SMF, UPF, etc.) by the process of subscriber's registration, so we can know how the 5G Core works in the registration process.

Bangkit Capstone Project

Cloud Engineer

May 2021 – Jul 2021

- Build FastAPI deployments
- · Create VMs, networks and firewalls
- Manage services for cloud resources

Internship at Malang City Communication and Information Service

Backend Developer

Jun 2020 – Aug 2020

- Build "Presensi Online" application using CodeIgniter
- Create and manage databases using mySQL

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE

UKM Djawa Telkom University

Coordinator of External Division

Apr 2019 - Apr 2020

- Responsible for relationships outside the organization
- Responsible for relationships with organizations on other campuses
- Responsible for holding meetings with representatives of members from each community
- As a mediator between organization and communities

JOMBANG STUDENT COMMUNITY (KOPAJA TELYU)

Coordinator of the Kopaja Roadshow PR Division

Dec 2018 - Jan 2019

- Responsible for organizing members to contact all of the schools that will be entered for campus socialization
- Responsible for organizing members to contact all of the speakers and the guest star
- As a mediator for reporting progress and agenda from the chief to the members
- Ensure the job desk for the division will run properly
- Experienced to planning and running the main event with the whole committee

Member of External Division

Mar 2018 - Mar 2020

- Maintain good relations with other communities
- As a mediator between campus and community

SKILLS

- Able to operate Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) and/or Google Workspace (Docs, Sheets, Slides, Forms, Drive)
- Have experience using Linux
- Have experience with Virtualization/Containerization/Orchestration (VM/Docker/Kubernetes)
- Have experience with Cloud Computing (GCP/AWS/Huawei Cloud)
- Have experience using some programming language (Python, C, Bash script)
- Have experience with Routing and Switching
- Have experience to configure an open-source 4G and 5G network

CERTIFICATIONS / LICENSES

HCIA Cloud Computing Sep 2020 – Sep 2023

Certificate No. 01010080280805089633746

HCIA Routing & Switching Oct 2020 – Oct 2023

Certificate No. 01010010139780805481667025

HCIA Security

Dec 2020 – Dec 2023

Certificate No. 01010030139780806289767568

AWARDS

National Level Huawei ICT Cloud Competition 2nd Winner Dec 2020

National Cloud Computing 2020 ICT Competition held by Huawei

Campus Level Huawei ICT Cloud Selection 3rd Winner Dec 2020

Campus Level Cloud Computing 2020 ICT Competition Selection held by Huawei

ADDITIONAL

Other: Just finished my thesis with title "5G Implementing and Performance Testing using USRP and SRSRAN Software"

Technical: Open5GS as core network, and SRSRAN + USRP as eNodeB

Languages: Indonesian, English